Prescott S. Bush Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Prescott S. Bush Papers.
undated, 1952-1962.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Bush, Prescott Sheldon.
22 linear feet.
Prescott S. Bush was born on 15 May 1895 to Samuel Prescott Bush and Flora Sheldon Bush and was raised in Columbus, Ohio. He received a B.A. from Yale University in 1917 and completed his Army career in 1919. Bush joined the firm of Brown Brothers and Company became a partner in 1930. In 1930. In 1921 he married Dorothy Walker. The couple had five children. A resident of Greenwich, CT, Bush was elected as a member of its representative town meeting. In 1933 he was elected as moderator, a post to which he was re-elected until his election to the United States Senate in 1952. Bush announced his intention not to run for re-election in 1961. He died in 1972.
MSS19910001
Biography
Prescott S. Bush was born on 15 Mary 1895 to Samuel Prescott Bush and Flora Sheldon Bush and was raised in Columbus, Ohio. He received a B.A. from Yale University in 1917 and completed his Army career in 1919. Bush joined the firm of Brown Brothers and Company became a partner in 1930. In 1921 he married Dorothy Walker. The couple had five children, one of whom, George Herbert Walker Bush, would become the forty-first President of the United States.
A resident of Greenwich, CT, Bush was elected as a member of its representative town meeting. In 1933 he was elected as moderator, a post to which he was re-elected until his election to the United States Senate in 1952. In 1947, he served as Chairman of the Connecticut Republican State Finance Committee and as Delegate-at-Large to the 1948 Republican National Convention.
Two years after experiencing a close loss in Connecticut's 1950 senatorial election, Bush defeated Abraham Ribicoff in a run to fill the seat left vacant by the death of Senator Brien McMahon. He was re-elected to the Senate in 1956. During his senatorial career, Bush served as a member of the Senate Committee on Banking and Currency, the Senate Committee on Public Works, the Committee on Armed Services, a congressional Joint Economic Committee, and the Special Committee on Aging.
Bush received national recognition as an advocate of fiscal responsibility in government, and sponsored a price stability amendment to the Employment Act of 1946. He also proposed to give the President the power to veto individual items in appropriations bills, and in bills authorizing federal departments and agencies to borrow from the Treasury. He took special interest in the national urban renewal program, and, following enactment of the Housing Act of 1954, convened a Connecticut Conference on Urban Renewal in Hartford. His work on this issue resulted in twenty-six Connecticut communities receiving over $150 million in federal grants, which gave Connecticut the highest per capita renewal program in the United States.
Another of Senator Bush's major legislative interests was flood and hurricane protection for New England communities. He drafted Public Law 71, the Bush Hurricane Survey Act, enabling Army engineers to develop a new program of community protection against hurricane tidal flooding. Along with Congressman John W. McCormack, the Democratic House Majority Leader, Bush cooperated to enact Public Law 685, the Bush-McCormack Act, which expedited the construction of local flood protection works. In addition, Bush played a leading role in the drafting of the Federal Highway Aid Act of 1956, which authorized the construction of the national system of interstate and defense highways.
While Senator, Bush remained active in the Republican party. In 1956, he served as Chairman for the Resolutions Committee of the Republican National Convention. Four years later, he chaired a subcommittee which drafted the widely acclaimed platform planks on economic growth, business and labor.
During his career, Prescott Bush served as director of several nationally known corporations, including the Columbia Broadcasting System, the Wanadium Corporation of America, and Prudential Insurance. For eight years, he was a member of the Executive Committee of the United States Golf Association, serving successively as Secretary, Vice President and President from 1928-1935.
Bush announced his intention not to run for re-election in 1961. He died in 1972.
Scope and Content
The collection contains biographical sketches, newspaper clippings, information on legislative bills, correspondence, texts of interviews and speeches, press releases, photographs of flood damage and films of television appearances, and scrapbooks. There is little to no personal or family items in the collection. The scrapbooks have been disassembled and photocopied for preservation and ease of use.
In 1966-1967, Prescott Bush conducted an oral history with the Oral History Research Office of Columbia University. A copy of this oral history is available as part of the Bush Papers (Dodd C 9736).
Arrangement
Series I: Biographical Information ( 1953-1962 )
Series II: Correspondence ( 1952-1954 )
Series III: Public Statements ( undated, 1955-1962 )
Series IV: Press Releases ( 1952-1962 )
Series V: Speeches ( 1953-1962 )
Series VI: Photographs and Films ( undated, 1955-1962 )
Series VII: Scrapbooks ( 1952-1962 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut's Congressional delegation. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk. See also, the Prescott Bush oral history (19667-1967, Columbia University, Dodd C 9736).
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Annual Report of the Town of Chaplin,1953. Dodd WF 145
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Greenwich (Conn.) Town Meeting.; United States. Congress. Senate.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854-); United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Banking and Currency.; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Public Works.; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Armed Services.; United States. Congress. Senate. Special Committee on Aging.; Federal Highway Program (U.S.); Hurricane protection—United States.; Republican National Convention.; Disaster relief—United States.; Connecticut—Politics and government—1951-
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Speeches.; Scrapbooks.; Photographs.; Press releases.; Newsletters.
Occupations:
Politician.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The Papers were deposited at the Connecticut State Library in 1963. In 1991, the papers were deaccessioned by the State Library and transferred to the University of Connecticut Libraries.
Acquisition Information
In 1991, the papers were deaccessioned by the State Library and transferred to the University of Connecticut Libraries. A deed of gift for the collection was executed by Prescott Bush, Jr. in October 1991.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Biographical Information, 1953-1962
  - Biographical sketch
    - 1955 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - 1955 October 1 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - 1956 August (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - 1959 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - 1959 October (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - 1961 January 1 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
    - 1961 August 15 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
    - 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
    - Condensed, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1958-1959 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Bills Introduced in 83rd Congress, 1953-1954 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Oral history, 1966-1967 (Other C 9736)
  - Voting Records, 86th Congress, 1st session, 1959 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1952-1954
  - Speaking engagements, 1952-1953 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - American Society of Newspaper Editors Reception, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - “Hats for Senators” Luncheon, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Television—Michael Goode, 1952-1954 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Radio Broadcasts—General, 1952-1954 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Radio Broadcast—WSTC (Stamford, CT), 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Broadcast—WNHC TV, 1953 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
- Series III: Public Statements, undated, 1955-1962
  - Statements
    - 1955 (Box 2:, Folder 22)
    - 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 23)
    - 1957 (Box 2:, Folder 24)
    - 1958 (Box 2:, Folder 25)
    - 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 26)
    - 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
    - 1961 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - 1962 (Box 2:, Folder 29)
  - WICC Broadcasts (Box 2:, Folder 30)
  - Television—General Sturgis, 1955 (Box 2:, Folder 31)
  - Television programs—General, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 32)
  - Television—Civil Defense for WICC (Bridgeport, CT), undated (Box 2:, Folder 33)
  - Television—Combined FEP, undated (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - Reports from Washington, 1961-1962 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
- Series IV: Press Releases, undated, 1952-1962
  - 1952 November (Box 3:, Folder 36)
  - 1952 December (Box 3:, Folder 37)
  - Resignation from directorates of publicly-owned companies, 1953 January 2 (Box 3:, Folder 38)
  - Death of Senator Brien McMahon, 1953 January 3 (Box 3:, Folder 39)
  - Wiggins Airlines Case, 1953 January 6 (Box 3:, Folder 40)
  - WTIC and WICC broadcasts, 1953 January 6 (Box 3:, Folder 41)
  - Filibusters—Cloture, 1953 January 8 (Box 3:, Folder 42)
  - President's Inaugural address, 1953 January 20 (Box 3:, Folder 43)
  - State control of Bradley Field, 1953 January 22 (Box 3:, Folder 44)
  - Metropolitan Golf Writers, 1953 January 27 (Box 3:, Folder 45)
  - President's State of the Union, 1953 February 2 (Box 3:, Folder 46)
  - Tax on copper, 1953 February 3 (Box 3:, Folder 47)
  - President's State of the Union, 1953 February 3 (Box 3:, Folder 48)
  - Patronage positions and appointments, 1953 February 4 (Box 3:, Folder 49)
  - Tariff, Trade Agreements Act; Yalta and Potsdam Agreements, 1953 February 5 (Box 3:, Folder 50)
  - Highway tolls, 1953 February 6 (Box 3:, Folder 51)
  - Claire Booth Luce as Ambassadress to Italy, 1953 February 7 (Box 3:, Folder 52)
  - Lincoln Day, 1953 February 8 (Box 3:, Folder 53)
  - Lincoln Day—Greenwich Republicans, 1953 February 11 (Box 3:, Folder 54)
  - Memorial for Senator McMahon, 1953 February 18 (Box 3:, Folder 55)
  - Senate statement—Senator McMahon, 1953 February 18 (Box 3:, Folder 56)
  - Washington's birthday observance, 1953 February 19 (Box 3:, Folder 57)
  - School aid; Lithuanian Independence Day; Claire Booth Luce, 1953 February 19 (Box 3:, Folder 58)
  - Academies, 1953 February 20 (Box 3:, Folder 59)
  - Profile—Barron's, 1953 February 20 (Box 3:, Folder 60)
  - Committee—hearings, 1953 February 26 (Box 3:, Folder 61)
  - S. 1081 temporary controls, 1953 February 27 (Box 3:, Folder 62)
  - Radio broadcast—Clarence H. Adams, 1953 March 3 (Box 3:, Folder 63)
  - Presidential Emergency powers; condemnation of Soviet repression of minorities; school aid appropriations, 1953 March 5 (Box 3:, Folder 64)
  - Stalin's death, 1953 March 6 (Box 3:, Folder 65)
  - Thomas G. Masavyk, 1953 March 7 (Box 3:, Folder 66)
  - Prisoner of War claims—deadline, 1953 March 14 (Box 3:, Folder 67)
  - Man of the Year Award dinner—State Street Debating Society, Ltd., 1953 March 16 (Box 3:, Folder 68)
  - Tax on baby formula, 1953 March 16 (Box 3:, Folder 69)
  - Foreign affairs, 1953 March 18 (Box 3:, Folder 70)
  - National Mental Health Week, 1953 March 19 (Box 3:, Folder 71)
  - War Damages Insurance; Atomic Bomb; Stalin's Death; William H. Taft, III, 1953 March 19 (Box 3:, Folder 72)
  - Jasper McNevy's 75th Birthday, 1953 March 20 (Box 3:, Folder 73)
  - Schuyler Merritt's death, 1953 April 2 (Box 3:, Folder 74)
  - Tidelands issue; Oil-for-Education, 1953 April 5 (Box 3:, Folder 75)
  - Naval Reserve Officers Training Corps, 1953 April 7 (Box 3:, Folder 76)
  - S. 261 Connecticut River Flood Control Compact, 1953 April 8 (Box 3:, Folder 77)
  - Taft-Hartley Act; amendments to Labor Management Act of 1947, 1953 April 9 (Box 3:, Folder 78)
  - S. 261 Connecticut River Flood Control, 1953 April 12 (Box 3:, Folder 79)
  - Clothing for Korean orphans, 1953 April 13 (Box 3:, Folder 80)
  - S. 1081 Controls; Critical Defense housing areas; Rent controls; Tidelands bill; Export-Import Bank, 1953 April 16 (Box 3:, Folder 81)
  - S. J. Res. 13 Tidelands bill; submerged land, 1953 April 21 (Box 3:, Folder 82)
  - Tabling of the Hill; Oil-for-Education amendment, 1953 April 27 (Box 3:, Folder 83)
  - Filibuster; Tidelands issue; McCarran Act; national mental health; Presidential Foreign policy address, 1953 April 30 (Box 3:, Folder 84)
  - Tidelands bill, 1953 May 5 (Box 3:, Folder 85)
  - S. 1081 Controls; Title VIII of S. 1081, 1953 May 13 (Box 3:, Folder 86)
  - Hawaii statehood; Communist movement in Hawaii Simpson Tariff bill; Reciprocal Trade Agreements Housing, 1953 May 14 (Box 3:, Folder 87)
  - FCC complaints in Waterbury, 1953 May 16 (Box 3:, Folder 88)
  - National Guard protest, 1953 May 17 (Box 3:, Folder 89)
  - Interest rates; Program for a Sound Dollar and Prevention of Inflation, 1953 May 26 (Box 3:, Folder 90)
  - Congressional salaries; Abolish the RFC; Excess Profits Tax; sound fiscal policies, 1953 May 28 (Box 3:, Folder 91)
  - Korean truce; tax reductions; military cuts in appropriations; national security; budget, 1953 June 11 (Box 3:, Folder 92)
  - Facts Forum, 1953 June 16 (Box 3:, Folder 93)
  - Death of George H. Walker, 1953 June 24 (Box 3:, Folder 94)
  - Canceled talk by Mrs. Bush, 1953 June 25 (Box 3:, Folder 95)
  - Senators Bush and Kerr, 1953 June 30 (Box 3:, Folder 96)
  - Budget, 83rd Congress; highway tolls; Air Force appropriations; Public Works Comm. Trip; Banking and Currency CT trip, 1953 July 9 (Box 3:, Folder 97)
  - S. 16 Judiciary Amendment Immunity Provisions—testimony before Congressional Committees, 1953 July 10 (Box 3:, Folder 98)
  - Anne Mitchell, 1953 July 15 (Box 3:, Folder 99)
  - Equal Rights Amendment—S.J. Res. 49, 1953 July 16 (Box 3:, Folder 100)
  - Post Office Deficits; Equal Rights; RFC; small business, 1953 July 23 (Box 3:, Folder 101)
  - Harold R. Somerset—Naval Academy, 1953 July 27 (Box 3:, Folder 102)
  - Korean truce, 1953 July 27 (Box 3:, Folder 103)
  - Simon S. Cohen nomination, 1953 July 27 (Box 3:, Folder 104)
  - Senate committee on Government Operations—S. 2473, 1953 July 29 (Box 3:, Folder 105)
  - Death of Robert A. Taft, 1953 July 31 (Box 3:, Folder 106)
  - Silver Purchase Law repeal, 1953 August 3 (Box 3:, Folder 107)
  - S. 2555 Silver Purchase Law, 1953 August 4 (Box 3:, Folder 108)
  - American Hebrew, 1953 August 4 (Box 3:, Folder 109)
  - Budget debt limit; fiscal problems; economy in government, 1953 August 6 (Box 3:, Folder 110)
  - Greenwich office; housing; Commission on Foreign Economic Policy appointment, 1953 August 13 (Box 3:, Folder 111)
  - CT Federation of Labor—convention, 1953 September 2 (Box 3:, Folder 112)
  - Tax changes in Internal Revenue Laws; Federal Aid to States; CT State Development Commission, 1953 September 8 (Box 3:, Folder 113)
  - S. 796 correspondence to Russell Swinger, 1953 September 15 (Box 3:, Folder 114)
  - Council on World Affairs, Women's Division luncheon, 1953 September 29 (Box 3:, Folder 115)
  - Danaher appointment, 1953 September 29 (Box 3:, Folder 116)
  - Commission on Foreign Economic Policy—exports and imports, 1953 October 8 (Box 3:, Folder 117)
  - CT Congregational Churches—Conference, Men's Dinner: moral law, 1953 October 8 (Box 3:, Folder 118)
  - Polish American Congress—175th anniversary of Count Pulaski's death, 1953 October 11 (Box 3:, Folder 119)
  - CT Association of Insurance Agents, 1953 October 14 (Box 3:, Folder 120)
  - High school speech—government, 1953 October 23 (Box 3:, Folder 121)
  - Capital Memo program, 1953 November 1 (Box 4:, Folder 122)
  - Banking and Security Committee, 1953 November 4 (Box 4:, Folder 123)
  - Election returns, 1953 November 4 (Box 4:, Folder 124)
  - Entrance exam for Coast Guard Academy, 1953 November 16 (Box 4:, Folder 125)
  - Budget information; tax, 1953 November 21 (Box 4:, Folder 126)
  - Amendments to SEC ads, 1953 November 25 (Box 4:, Folder 127)
  - Foreign policy; Communism; McCarthy-Eisenhower statement, 1953 December 3 (Box 4:, Folder 128)
  - Eisenhower's U.N. statement, 1953 December 9 (Box 4:, Folder 129)
  - REP Committee -Paris trip, 1953 December 11 (Box 4:, Folder 130)
  - Jewish Ledger, 1954 January 4 (Box 4:, Folder 131)
  - President's State of the Union, 1954 January 7 (Box 4:, Folder 132)
  - Elmore, Lyon, Leete—banking, 1954 January 11 (Box 4:, Folder 133)
  - Area 3 bills: New Haven Harbor to Housatonic River; Area 7: Housatonic River to Ash Creek, 1954 January 12 (Box 4:, Folder 134)
  - Broadcast—WTIC, 1954 January 14 (Box 4:, Folder 135)
  - “The Big Issue”, 1954 January 18 (Box 4:, Folder 136)
  - Judge Anderson appointment, 1954 January 18 (Box 4:, Folder 137)
  - Arms; ammunitions bill, 1954 January 18 (Box 4:, Folder 138)
  - Improve Patchogue River bill, 1954 January 18 (Box 4:, Folder 139)
  - Bricker Amendment, 1954 January 21 (Box 4:, Folder 140)
  - Randall Commission report, 1954 January 23 (Box 4:, Folder 141)
  - Foreign Economic Policy Commission, 1954 January 23 (Box 4:, Folder 142)
  - Sunday Star—Herbert Brather, 1954 January 27 (Box 4:, Folder 143)
  - Bricker Amendment, 1954 January 28 (Box 4:, Folder 144)
  - John A. Danaher, 1954 February 2 (Box 4:, Folder 145)
  - Judge Carroll C. Hincks, 1954 February 2 (Box 4:, Folder 146)
  - S. 2846 Amending the Acts administered by the SEC, 1954 February 3 (Box 4:, Folder 147)
  - National Amateur Radio Week, 1954 February 4 (Box 4:, Folder 148)
  - Potato situation, 1954 February 4 (Box 4:, Folder 149)
  - Lincoln Day: Waterbury, 1954 February 12 (Box 4:, Folder 150)
  - Farm policy—FEP, 1954 February 18 (Box 4:, Folder 151)
  - Shooting; Hawaii; George Amendment, 1954 March 4 (Box 4:, Folder 152)
  - McCarthyism, 1954 March 18 (Box 4:, Folder 153)
  - Taxes, 1954 March 23 (Box 4:, Folder 154)
  - Bernie Yudain, 1954 March 30 (Box 4:, Folder 155)
  - President's message on Foreign Economic Policy, 1954 March 30 (Box 4:, Folder 156)
  - Tax Relief program, 1954 April 1 (Box 4:, Folder 157)
  - S. 796; Federal aid to highways, 1954 April 7 (Box 4:, Folder 158)
  - New Haven toll road, 1954 April 9 (Box 4:, Folder 159)
  - Housing—FHA “mess”, 1954 April 15 (Box 4:, Folder 160)
  - S. 3114 Health Insurance bill, 1954 April 25 (Box 4:, Folder 161)
  - Housing scandal, 1954 April 29 (Box 4:, Folder 162)
  - FHA—B and C Committee; federal aid to highways, 1954 May 6 (Box 4:, Folder 163)
  - Cheshire-McCarthy—procedures code, 1954 May 15 (Box 4:, Folder 164)
  - Foreign policy—segregation, 1954 May 20 (Box 4:, Folder 165)
  - Code for Investigations, 1954 May 24 (Box 4:, Folder 166)
  - Pierce J. Gerety appointment, 1954 May 26 (Box 4:, Folder 167)
  - U.S. Tariff Committee—Wood screw, 1954 May 26 (Box 4:, Folder 168)
  - S. 2473—Government Operations Committee, 1954 June 2 (Box 4:, Folder 169)
  - Procedures—review of Administration, 1954 June 17 (Box 4:, Folder 170)
  - S. Res. 253—Rules committee, 1954 June 24 (Box 4:, Folder 171)
  - Essentiality of watch industry, 1954 June 30 (Box 4:, Folder 172)
  - Independence Day speech—Fairfield, CT, 1954 July 5 (Box 4:, Folder 173)
  - Watch industry tariff—President's decision, 1954 July 27 (Box 4:, Folder 174)
  - S. 2846 State on the Floor, 1954 July 28 (Box 4:, Folder 175)
  - Flander's censure of McCarthy; S. 3076 Communist Party Humphrey Amendment, 1954 July 31 (Box 4:, Folder 176)
  - 83rd Congress, end of session statement, 1954 August 20 (Box 4:, Folder 177)
  - Bristol—Rotary and Republican Women's Club; Tax reform, 1954 September 14 (Box 4:, Folder 178)
  - Watkins Committee Report, 1954 September 27 (Box 4:, Folder 179)
  - Tariff and Trade Policies—New London LWV, 1954 October 6 (Box 4:, Folder 180)
  - Hamden Town Hall; Republican Rally; FHA Scandals, 1954 October 7 (Box 4:, Folder 181)
  - New Haven, Shrine Club; Communism; Anti-Subversive Bill, 1954 October 8 (Box 4:, Folder 182)
  - Inter-Regional Competition, 1954 October 15 (Box 4:, Folder 183)
  - Code of Fair procedures, 1954 October 19 (Box 4:, Folder 184)
  - Republican National Committee FHA scandal, 1954 October 19 (Box 4:, Folder 185)
  - New Britain Lions Club FHA scandal, 1954 October 19 (Box 4:, Folder 186)
  - New Haven Kiwanis Club vote of confidence for Eisenhower, 1954 October 27 (Box 4:, Folder 187)
  - Coast Guard Academy exam, 1954 November 4 (Box 4:, Folder 188)
  - Senate rules additions [Watkins], 1954 November 9 (Box 4:, Folder 189)
  - State Street Bridge Crossing Investigation, 1954 November 12 (Box 4:, Folder 190)
  - Wood screw industry, 1954 November 17 (Box 4:, Folder 191)
  - McCarthy censure recess, 1954 November 19 (Box 4:, Folder 192)
  - Brady Homes; PHA, 1954 December 3 (Box 4:, Folder 193)
  - McCarthy's statement against President, 1954 December 7 (Box 4:, Folder 194)
  - Federal budget; Humphrey, 1954 December 7 (Box 4:, Folder 195)
  - President's reply to McCarthy, 1954 December 8 (Box 4:, Folder 196)
  - Tanner letter [In Lieu of Taxes and Shared Revenues], 1954 December 9 (Box 4:, Folder 197)
  - Hotel bond; Republican luncheon; American prisoners, 1954 December 14 (Box 4:, Folder 198)
  - State of the Union, 1955 January 6 (Box 4:, Folder 199)
  - Welles Village sale to Glastonbury, 1955 January 10 (Box 4:, Folder 200)
  - President on Foreign economic policy, 1955 January 10 (Box 4:, Folder 201)
  - Stock investigations, 1955 January 10 (Box 4:, Folder 202)
  - Code of Fair Procedures, 1955 January 14 (Box 4:, Folder 203)
  - Release on Keats, 1955 January 16 (Box 4:, Folder 204)
  - NIKE No. 1, 1955 January 16 (Box 4:, Folder 205)
  - President's message on budget, 1955 January 17 (Box 4:, Folder 206)
  - Westport—NIKE, 1955 January 19 (Box 4:, Folder 207)
  - President's economic message, 1955 January 20 (Box 4:, Folder 208)
  - FEP; minimum wage; budget, 1955 January 21 (Box 4:, Folder 209)
  - Radio Amateur Week bill, 1955 January 21 (Box 4:, Folder 210)
  - Foreign Economic Policy—Waugh, 1955 January 24 (Box 4:, Folder 211)
  - League of Women Voters, 1955 January 24 (Box 4:, Folder 212)
  - Hurricane bill—correspondence, 1955 January 26 (Box 4:, Folder 213)
  - Television—NIKE No. 2, 1955 January 30 (Box 5:, Folder 214)
  - Governor Ribicoff—shore erosion, 1955 February 2 (Box 5:, Folder 215)
  - Flemming; Navigation project; Thames River, 1955 February 2 (Box 5:, Folder 216)
  - Health program; Formossa issue, 1955 February 2 (Box 5:, Folder 217)
  - Hurricane—correspondence, 1955 February 4 (Box 5:, Folder 218)
  - FEP—Randall, 1955 February 13 (Box 5:, Folder 219)
  - Face the Nation, 1955 February 13 (Box 5:, Folder 220)
  - Air Force Academy list, 1955 February 16 (Box 5:, Folder 221)
  - League of Women Voters, 1955 February 17 (Box 5:, Folder 222)
  - Statement for Lithuania, 1955 February 18 (Box 5:, Folder 223)
  - Emergency school construction, 1955 February 19 (Box 5:, Folder 224)
  - Governor Ribicoff—Highway bill, 1955 March 1 (Box 5:, Folder 225)
  - Civil Defense—Peterson, 1955 March 13 (Box 5:, Folder 226)
  - Extra Federal Judge in CT bill, 1955 March 16 (Box 5:, Folder 227)
  - Ribicoff—Highway bill, 1955 March 18 (Box 5:, Folder 228)
  - Stock market inquiry to Garrett, Cronan, 1955 March 18 (Box 5:, Folder 229)
  - Highway with Don Larrabee, 1955 March 18 (Box 5:, Folder 230)
  - Urban Renewal Conference, 1955 March 21 (Box 5:, Folder 231)
  - S. 414 hearing, 1955 March 23 (Box 5:, Folder 232)
  - President Eisenhower; bike manufacturers, 1955 March 23 (Box 5:, Folder 233)
  - Dr. Brownell, 1955 March 27 (Box 5:, Folder 234)
  - Urban Renewal Conference, 1955 March 28 (Box 5:, Folder 235)
  - S. 1577 CT Road bill, 1955 March 30 (Box 5:, Folder 236)